Dmitriy Vasilyuk

510 851 1078



vasilyuk.dm@gmail.com



github.com/reasonmethis



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Transitioned from Ph.D. program in theoretical particle physics to successful 14+ year career as professional poker player and now full stack blockchain developer and algorithmic trader. Success in these endeavors due to battle-tested math, CS, and data science skills. Passion for science, philosophy, and critical thinking translates to well-thought-out solutions and writings.

SKILLS

Tech: Python, JavaScript, C++, Solidity, TypeScript, SQL, React, NumPy, Matplotlib, Pandas, Scikitlearn, NLTK, Flask, Web3, MUI

Fundamentals: theoretical physics, graduate level math, algorithms & data structures, stats, ML, game theory, cryptocurrency

Miscellaneous: poker, analytic philosophy, scientific skepticism, teaching, writing & editing, 5 languages, accessibility issues/tools

WORK EXPERIENCE

Blockchain Developer and Algo Trader – Emeryville, CA

Aug 2021 - Present

- Build full stack decentralized app (Solidity contract + React front end) and perpetual futures trading bot (on Solana)
- Build suite of time-series analysis and monitoring tools (Python data science stack) for trading/investing in DeFi projects

Professional Poker Player - Emeryville, CA

May 2007 – Oct 2021

- Beat mid & high stakes limit hold'em games with winrate 1.9BB/100 over last 1M hands on PokerStars and other sites
- Succeeded by building applications (with Python, C++ see below) to help play, analyze strategies, alert to weaknesses

Co-founder of small software company Q-Wager – El Cerrito, CA

Jun 2006 – Aug 2009

Built C++ app to beat online casinos by optimally auto-playing blackjack and collecting bonuses, 300+ paying customers

PROJECTS

View publicly deployed projects: Bet Czar • Crypto Analyzer • ReasonMeThis • VocabMeThis • Kristoshka

View **GitHub**

Bet Czar {React, TS, Solidity, Hardhat, MUI, Ethers} – decentralized application to manage and enforce bets on the blockchain

- Focus on security and UX: guards against contract exploits, gas optimizations, clean responsive UI, user guidance & docs
- Original: many today's DeFi apps copy concept/contracts/UI logic from other projects Bet Czar is "baked from scratch"

Crypto Trader {Python: 3200 lines} – trading bots for Ethereum VM compatible blockchains and Solana

- Solana bot (a) runs market-making strategy for perp futures; (b) places +EV taker orders based on orderbook and oracle
- EVM bot queries liquidity pool smart contracts and executes **on-chain swaps** based on predefined triggers, sends alerts

Poker Analyzer {Python: 6800 lines} – game analysis suite: advanced filters & stats, detects players' weaknesses during game

- During play parses game history, adds to custom-made database, updates all stats, reports deviations from reference
- Rich query language to filter player game data and 89GB of Nash equilibrium strategy, generates reports & quizzes
- Monte-Carlo sims of equilibrium & non-equilibrium play to calculate EVs and find exploitative strategy adjustments

PROJECTS continued

Crypto Analyzer {Python: 4500 lines} – Telegram bot with a suite of tools for analyzing and monitoring crypto price data

- Fetches live & historical prices, calculates autocorrelation, volatility, trends, impermanent loss, makes graphical reports
- Each user can set one's own parameters and create alerts to monitor crypto positions; public vs advanced features

VocabMeThis {Python, Flask} – mobile-friendly web app to test user's vocabulary and teach new words at auto-adjusting level

- 125000 words & definitions, with algorithm to rank by difficulty by constructing frequency dictionary from NLTK corpora
- Data cleaning algorithms to identity different forms of the same word, replace one-word definitions with proper ones

Game Manager {C++: 7400 lines} – application to monitor & manage poker tables and play without needing mouse or keyboard

- Analyzes mic sound, classifies it (S vs SH vs AH etc.), translates into required action on poker table, adapts to noise
- Monitors poker tables for special events (opponent came, good seat freed up, etc.), alerts and performs needed action

ReasonMeThis {HTML, CSS, JavaScript} - philosophy, physics, and critical thinking blog at www.reasonmethis.com

- Over 30 articles on philosophy of language, anthropic reasoning, multiverse, entropy, consciousness, and other topics
- Custom HTML and CSS, responsive JavaScript animations of physics and math concepts

EDUCATION

Master of Arts in Physics – UC Berkeley

2006

- Conducted research in string theory as part of Ph.D. program, switched careers before finishing Ph.D.
- Completed coursework in quantum field theory, general relativity, string theory, differentiable manifolds, Lie groups
- Received Outstanding Graduate Student Instructor award for excellence in teaching

Bachelor of Arts in Physics – *UC Berkeley*

1999

■ Earned 2nd place in BAUPC '99, Harvard-run physics competition